{"choices":[{"question":"Which of the following permutation in \\(S_7\\) commutes with \\(\\theta = \\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3 &amp; 4 &amp; 5 &amp; 6 &amp; 7\\\\ 1 &amp; 5 &amp; 4 &amp; 3 &amp; 7 &amp; 6 &amp; 2 \\end {pmatrix}\\)? ","answers":["<p>\\(\\sigma = \\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3 &amp; 4 &amp; 5 &amp; 6 &amp; 7\\\\ 6 &amp; 2 &amp; 4 &amp; 3 &amp; 5 &amp; 1 &amp; 7 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\sigma = \\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3 &amp; 4 &amp; 5 &amp; 6 &amp; 7\\\\ 1 &amp; 3 &amp; 4 &amp; 5 &amp; 6 &amp; 7 &amp; 2 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\sigma = \\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3 &amp; 4 &amp; 5 &amp; 6 &amp; 7\\\\ 2 &amp; 5 &amp; 4 &amp; 3 &amp; 7 &amp; 6 &amp; 1 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>","<p>none of the other three<\/p>"],"subContentId":"b5640e5e-d316-497e-b3d5-7091a9ef0226"},{"question":"Let \\(\\theta , \\sigma \\in S_5\\) be given by \\(\\sigma = \\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3 &amp; 4 &amp; 5 \\\\ 2 &amp; 5 &amp; 1 &amp; 3 &amp; 4 \\end {pmatrix}\\) and \\(\\theta = \\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3 &amp; 4 &amp; 5 \\\\ 4 &amp; 5 &amp; 3 &amp; 2 &amp; 1 \\end {pmatrix}\\). Then \\(\\sigma \\circ \\theta \\) maps \\(2\\) to ____________ and the image of \\(2\\) under \\(\\sigma \\theta \\) is ____________","answers":["<p>\\(4, 1\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(1, 4\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(1, 1\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(4, 4\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"ef15542d-9eec-478b-400b-c6d601f7c5f4"},{"question":"Let \\(\\theta , \\sigma \\in S_n\\). Then the product \\(\\theta \\sigma = \\)____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(\\sigma \\circ \\theta \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\sigma \\theta \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\theta \\circ \\sigma \\)<\/p>","<p>not always defined<\/p>"],"subContentId":"7818ba6c-e6fb-4f55-06cc-0ddbf8e37781"},{"question":"In the standard notation, \\(\\varphi \\in S_3\\) is given by ","answers":["<p>\\(\\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3\\\\ 2 &amp; 1 &amp; 3 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3\\\\ 2 &amp; 3 &amp; 1 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3\\\\ 3 &amp; 1 &amp; 2 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3\\\\ 3 &amp; 2 &amp; 1 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"fe82500f-b4c7-44d4-e4d5-af78a5d3fe1f"},{"question":"In the standard notation, \\(\\psi \\in S_3\\) is given by ","answers":["<p>\\(\\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3\\\\ 2 &amp; 3 &amp; 1 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3\\\\ 2 &amp; 1 &amp; 3 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3\\\\ 3 &amp; 1 &amp; 2 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\begin {pmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3\\\\ 3 &amp; 2 &amp; 1 \\end {pmatrix}\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"cf6993ca-4b86-4286-d722-b5ea00d15261"},{"question":"In the standard notation, the inverse of \\(\\varphi \\in S_3\\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(\\varphi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\psi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\psi \\varphi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\varphi \\psi \\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"e134abea-ec59-455d-2bbf-375a69c141f2"},{"question":"In the standard notation, the inverse of \\(\\psi \\in S_3\\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(\\psi ^2\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\psi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\varphi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\varphi \\psi \\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"2e9d232e-16fb-45ec-4eff-49ed64cc2e7f"},{"question":"In the standard notation, the inverse of \\(\\psi ^2 \\in S_3\\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(\\psi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\varphi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\psi ^2\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\varphi \\psi \\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"e1b0b70d-65b4-4584-9ef0-0bc08997847a"},{"question":"In the standard notation, the inverse of \\(\\varphi \\psi \\in S_3\\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(\\varphi \\psi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\psi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\varphi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\psi \\varphi \\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"72705bb8-5578-4a2f-b173-25e8c9de1cfc"},{"question":"The number of self-inverse elements (i.e., inverse of itself) in \\(S_3\\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(4\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(1\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(2\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(3\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"0a960932-c94d-4fa6-37cf-f115e1e14ed8"},{"question":"The number of elements in \\(S_3\\) which are not self-inverses (i.e., which are not inverses of itself) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(2\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(1\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(3\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(4\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"745f5493-47b8-4e64-22e0-3f532d857dd7"},{"question":"Let \\(T = \\{x \\in S_3 \\mid x \\neq e,\\ x^3 = e\\}\\). Then the cardinality of the set \\(T\\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(2\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(1\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(3\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(4\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"83bd8a58-9626-42e9-e824-5800936a57e8"},{"question":"In the standard notation, in \\(S_3\\), \\(\\psi ^2 \\varphi \\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(\\varphi \\psi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\psi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\varphi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\psi \\varphi \\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"17eb2566-6875-4483-289c-dcd10e7f48a5"},{"question":"In the standard notation, in \\(S_3\\), \\((\\varphi \\psi )(\\psi \\varphi ) = \\) ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(\\psi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\varphi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(e\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\psi ^2\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"8131465b-afc1-4b05-9d64-2b33c8738d72"},{"question":"Let \\(G\\) be a group. The group \\(A(G)\\) is non-abelian if and only if ","answers":["<p>none of the other three<\/p>","<p>\\(|G| \\ge 2\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(G\\) is finite<\/p>","<p>\\(G\\) is infinite<\/p>"],"subContentId":"88527233-d830-4b60-8f9f-7380f2ca5fea"},{"question":"For any symbol \\(a\\) and some fixed \\(n \\in \\mathbb N\\), the set \\(\\{a^0, a, a^2, \\ldots, a^{n}\\}\\) such that \\(a^{n+1} = a^0 = e\\) is ____________ under the following operation: \\[a^i a^j = \\left \\{\\begin {array}{ll} a^{i+j} &amp;\\ \\text { if } i + j \\le n\\\\ a^{i+j-n-1} &amp;\\ \\text { if } i + j &gt; n \\end {array}\\right .\\] ","answers":["<p>an abelian group of order \\(n+1\\)<\/p>","<p>a cyclic group of order \\(n\\)<\/p>","<p>not a cyclic group of order \\(n+1\\)<\/p>","<p>not a group<\/p>"],"subContentId":"80bfc9eb-30c1-46f9-4bba-74a8d9541490"},{"question":"Let \\(a, b, c\\) be elements of a group \\(G\\). Then the inverse of their product \\(abc\\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(c^{-1}b^{-1}a^{-1}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(a^{-1}b^{-1}c^{-1}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(c^{-1} ab^{-1}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(a^{-1}c^{-1}b^{-1}\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"ab969a96-850d-415e-dd58-818094a36506"},{"question":"Let \\(G\\) be a group and \\(H\\) and \\(K\\) be subgroups of \\(G\\). Then ____________is necessarily a subgroup of \\(G\\). ","answers":["<p>\\(H \\cap K\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(H \\cup K\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(HK\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(H+K\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"bd3536f2-7dbb-44dd-4b86-f1663154faed"},{"question":"Which of the following sets is not a subgroup of \\(A(\\mathbb Z)\\)? ","answers":["<p>\\(\\{\\sigma \\in A(\\mathbb Z) \\mid \\sigma (n) \\neq n \\text { for all but finitely many } n \\in \\mathbb Z\\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{\\sigma \\in A(\\mathbb Z) \\mid \\sigma (n) = n \\text { for all but finitely many } n \\in \\mathbb Z\\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{\\sigma \\in A(\\mathbb Z) \\mid \\sigma (n) = n \\text { for all } n \\in \\mathbb Z\\}\\)<\/p>","<p>none of the other three<\/p>"],"subContentId":"d591884c-210b-4717-5931-2a7f5458c27d"},{"question":"Let \\(S\\) be a nonempty set and \\(x_0, x_1 \\in S\\). Which of the following is a subgroup of \\(A(S)\\)? ","answers":["<p>\\(\\{\\phi \\in A(S) \\mid \\phi (x_0) = x_0,\\ \\phi (x_1) = x_1\\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{\\phi \\in A(S) \\mid \\phi (x_0) = x_1\\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{\\phi \\in A(S) \\mid \\phi (x_0) = x_1,\\ \\phi (x_1) = x_0\\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{\\phi \\in A(S) \\mid \\phi (x_0) \\neq x_0\\}\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"292e0043-025b-4141-75a3-f6290a255e82"},{"question":"In \\(S_3\\), the cyclic subgroup generated by \\(\\varphi \\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(\\{e, \\varphi \\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{e, \\varphi , \\varphi \\psi , \\psi \\varphi \\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{\\varphi \\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{\\varphi , \\psi \\}\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"e3e31599-e164-4ce9-2724-81826220d2b9"},{"question":"In \\(S_3\\), the cyclic subgroup generated by \\(\\psi \\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(\\{e, \\psi , \\psi ^2\\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{e, \\psi \\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{\\psi \\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{e, \\psi , \\psi \\varphi , \\varphi \\psi \\}\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"5889c29c-07aa-49c0-db79-f50765ee2d80"},{"question":"In \\(S_3\\), the cyclic subgroup generated by \\(\\psi ^2\\) is ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(\\{e, \\psi , \\psi ^2\\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{e, \\psi ^2\\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{\\psi ^2\\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{e, \\psi ^2, \\psi \\varphi , \\varphi \\psi \\}\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"8bd54abb-263a-45c5-62e0-29ded3ecbab5"},{"question":"In \\(S_3\\), the cyclic subgroup generated by ____________is same ","answers":["<p>\\(\\psi \\) and \\(\\psi ^2\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\psi \\) and \\(\\varphi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\varphi \\psi \\) and \\(\\psi \\varphi \\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\varphi \\) and \\(\\psi ^2\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"501b3df6-d4fc-4ecc-3d64-49d3dad7a323"},{"question":"Let \\(W = \\{\\varphi , \\psi \\}\\) be a subset of \\(S_3\\). In usual notations, \\((W) = \\) ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\(S_3\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(W\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{e, \\varphi , \\psi \\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{e, \\psi , \\psi \\varphi , \\varphi \\psi \\}\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"12b37e12-19e1-4ee3-10b8-0423e4562638"},{"question":"Let \\(W = \\{\\varphi \\psi \\}\\) be a subset of \\(S_3\\). In usual notations, \\((W) = \\) ____________. ","answers":["<p>\\( \\{e,\\varphi \\psi \\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(\\{e,\\varphi \\psi , \\psi \\varphi \\}\\)<\/p>","<p>\\(S_3\\)<\/p>","<p>\\( \\{\\varphi , \\psi \\}\\)<\/p>"],"subContentId":"880e3eda-eeb2-42b0-1849-cb5442a2517d"}],"overallFeedback":[{"from":0,"to":100}],"behaviour":{"autoContinue":false,"timeoutCorrect":2000,"timeoutWrong":3000,"soundEffectsEnabled":true,"enableRetry":true,"enableSolutionsButton":true,"passPercentage":100},"l10n":{"nextButtonLabel":"Next question","showSolutionButtonLabel":"Show solution","retryButtonLabel":"Retry","solutionViewTitle":"Solution list","correctText":"Correct!","incorrectText":"Incorrect!","shouldSelect":"Should have been selected","shouldNotSelect":"Should not have been selected","muteButtonLabel":"Mute feedback sound","closeButtonLabel":"Close","slideOfTotal":"Slide :num of :total","scoreBarLabel":"You got :num out of :total points","solutionListQuestionNumber":"Question :num","a11yShowSolution":"Show the solution. The task will be marked with its correct solution.","a11yRetry":"Retry the task. Reset all responses and start the task over again."}}